Hansol Ryu: Hello?
Victoria Wood: Hello!
Hansol Ryu: Sorry, I didn't hear you, but let me see.
Hansol Ryu: Right, can you say something?
Victoria Wood: Yeah, can you hear me now?
Hansol Ryu: Yes, I can hear you.
Victoria Wood: Awesome.
Victoria Wood: How are you doing?
Hansol Ryu: Being alright, huh? Managing many deadlines around, but surviving.
Victoria Wood: Yeah, how was WCV?
Victoria Wood: Oh, can you hear me?
Victoria Wood: I lost you.
Victoria Wood: Oh, I think you're back now.
Hansol Ryu: Hmm.
Victoria Wood: Can you hear me?
Hansol Ryu: Yeah, I can hear you. I think my Wi-Fi is not super stable, so let me try to reconnect.
Victoria Wood: Okay.
Hansol Ryu: Thank you.
Victoria Wood: You think that your internet connection's more stable now?
Hansol Ryu: Hello, can you hear me now?
Hansol Ryu: Alright, do you see my screen?
Victoria Wood: I do, yes.
Hansol Ryu: Let's see whether videos play.
Victoria Wood: Yeah, they're playing. There's no sound, but they're playing.
Hansol Ryu: Yeah, no sound, yeah, yeah.
Victoria Wood: Cool.
Hansol Ryu: Cool.
Victoria Wood: Cool, and then you have the sign-in, awesome, I'll put that in the chat as well when you're…
Victoria Wood: Okay, we normally give people, like, a minute or two after the hour starts, just to… Join in.
Hansol Ryu: Sounds good.
Victoria Wood: So start at, like, 12.02 or so.
Hansol Ryu: Hi, Kisa!
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: Hi, Hansol! How are you?
Hansol Ryu: Good, how are you?
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: I'm good, it's nice to see you!
Hansol Ryu: Yeah, good to see you!
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: Hi, Casey.
Casey King: Hi, Kiisa, how's it going?
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: Good.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: Finally sort of recovered from the jet lag of the… trip to Europe.
Casey King: That's great, that's great.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: I'm gonna go grab a paper and a pencil, and I'll be right back.
Hansol Ryu: Oh, whoa.
Hansol Ryu: Yeah, she knows much better than me about muscles, but…
Hansol Ryu: Maybe. Can you show this?
Victoria Wood: We might want to wait just another minute till we start, but,
Victoria Wood: now that we have a group here, I just did want to give one quick reminder, that we have that Google form, if you are a non-MC employee, so any of our trainees, or near-peer mentors, or anybody who isn't funded on MC year-round,
Victoria Wood: We have that form to fill out if you're interested in traveling to the Capstone Symposium, so please fill that out by Sunday, I'll put the link in the chat in just a second, and then we'll announce early next week, what the funding situation looks like once we have a better understanding of everybody's interest.
Victoria Wood: And let me know if you have any questions about that.
Victoria Wood: That's the only announcement that I have for right now, and I think, we can probably go ahead and start. So, Hansol, when you're ready…
Victoria Wood: Feel free.
Hansol Ryu: Alright, sounds good. Thank you, everyone, for joining today. I'm going to run an workshop on biophysical muscle models. I will start by giving a brief overview of the muscle model, and we will have a chance to play with the code, actually.
Hansol Ryu: Oops.
Hansol Ryu: Here is the sign-in link, if you didn't do it yet.
Hansol Ryu: Alright, let's get started.
Hansol Ryu: It may sound really obvious, but sometimes I find it a little bit surprising to think about all the muscles that are generating movement.
Hansol Ryu: So, when we move, basically everything comes from the muscle. The muscles are pulling our bones and moving our bodies.
Hansol Ryu: So, about modeling the muscles, I'd like to see how people are familiar with the muscle models. There's the reaction button on the Zoom, so can you indicate whether you heard about his high muscle model by pulling thumbs up?
Hansol Ryu: And if you heard about Close Blades, this is the clip.
Hansol Ryu: And then if you are not familiar with either of those, please, do the…
Hansol Ryu: Surprise one. Okay, some thumbs up for the hilt-time model. How about closely exists?
Hansol Ryu: Okay, a little bit.
Hansol Ryu: Huh.
Hansol Ryu: Anyone who kind of never heard about the muscle motives?
Hansol Ryu: Alright, yeah, alright, cool, cool, alright, thank you.
Hansol Ryu: So these muscle models are crucial for neural mechanical simulation of movement and posture control. And I will say that there are, like, locally two ways we use muscle models.
Hansol Ryu: One is for doing simulation of movement and balance control, and I'm using it for forward simulation of balance control. So, for people on a person on a perturbation platform while an animal, there are muscles that are driving the balance response.
Hansol Ryu: And I'd like to study the optimal contour strategies, or how the contour changes when something happens… some… something changes in your body or in your neural pathways. So I modeled this kind of an,
Hansol Ryu: Pertturbation response using an inverted pendulum model, and then put our muscle models, and then see what is the optimal fit forward right feedback strategies.
Hansol Ryu: Another way that is commonly used in biomechanics is estimating muscle force from the measurement.
Hansol Ryu: So, maybe some of you have experience working with OpenSIM models, so you can input your measurements of motion capture forces and
Hansol Ryu: play follow the EMG signaler, and then put it into the OpenZene model, and then use the model to estimate how much forces are generated by each of the muscles.
Hansol Ryu: So, to do this kind of simulations or estimations, we need a good model of a muscle. So, how much force the muscle generates given its force or, I'm sorry, given its activation, or length or velocity.
Hansol Ryu: So, there are, luckily two types of doprosyes in… Estimating muscle force.
Hansol Ryu: And I will talk about the conventional, or more commonly used way first, before moving on to our biophysical muscle model.
Hansol Ryu: So, plus one is that we can measure muscle forces at various lengths and velocities, and use that relationship to calculate the muscle force.
Hansol Ryu: It is known that for the muscles, there is an optimal length, so here is the first length curve that we also saw from the previous workshops.
Hansol Ryu: And then we will say that muscle force is simply the multiplication of activation, force length, and force velocity curves.
Hansol Ryu: And this one we would describe as a phenomenological model, and hilt-type muscle model is a type of a penalogical muscle model.
Hansol Ryu: But the problem of using such a model is that it doesn't capture any history-dependent properties, because you can see here, the muscle force is simply the function of activation, and it's
Hansol Ryu: colant length and column to velocity, and there is no way to capture the history. Histoly meaning how much activation the muscle had before coming to the colon stage, or what was the length or velocity before coming to this colant stage.
Hansol Ryu: But when you look at the actual muscle, muscles have quite a lot of history dependence. Here is the conditioner stretch of a single muscle fiber.
Hansol Ryu: So it is going through lengthening, shortening, lengthening, and then this portion of lengthening must be same as this portion when we go through the same velocity and same length change. But when you, when you look at the force developed by the muscle fiber.
Hansol Ryu: Here, force it to come from here.
Hansol Ryu: Maybe because… Maybe, because the muscle here was coming from the resting state, And the muscle here.
Hansol Ryu: Do you see my mouse, by the way?
Hansol Ryu: Oh yeah, cool, same. Yeah, so I'm also here… Sure.
Hansol Ryu: Yep, here, when it's going through the second straight, it was already moving before they're…
Hansol Ryu: So, the force it produces is different, but when you plug in the Hilltime muscle, you will end up with the same amount of force.
Hansol Ryu: But just a little note that actually Hill reported many of the history-dependent properties of the muscles, so it is not the root of the hill, but it is about the hill-type muscle model that is lacking the history dependence.
Hansol Ryu: This kind of a histoly dependence depends on the recent activation or latent movement, is observed on multiple levels.
Hansol Ryu: As I say, it is observed at fiber level, and it is also observed at the muscle level. This is a nice clip from Simon's lab. So, if you look here, the muscle is undergoing same type of a length change.
Hansol Ryu: Here.
Hansol Ryu: However, these different colors are indicating the different history of the muscles before coming to this part of the cycle.
Hansol Ryu: And you can see that the force developed by the muscles are dependent on its history.
Hansol Ryu: We also see history dependence on the movement level. Here is the glove from the, cellular PARTY participant. So, it is a clinical test called knee pendulum test. So, when you drop the knee from above.
Hansol Ryu: And make the leg swing like a pendulum.
Hansol Ryu: This is how it swings the black line when the leg was held still before the drop.
Hansol Ryu: And the orange line is showing how the leg swings if the leg was moved before the drop.
Hansol Ryu: So even though they drop from the same height, they will oscillate differently because of the different tests.
Hansol Ryu: So, hilt-time model does not capture any of these history dependents, so it is not suitable for some of our, projects.
Hansol Ryu: So, we come up with a different approach of calculating muscle forces based on the muscle contraction mechanism, rather than looking at its overall effect and summarizing it using force angles and false realistic curve alone.
Hansol Ryu: So, we will say muscle force is, summation of the close-speed forces, N…
Hansol Ryu: We will calculate the probability of attachment and detached month, which I will go into more in details later. And then…
Hansol Ryu: These, close bridge states are dependent on the pest activation and test movement, so by doing so, we will get the history dependence as an emerging property of the muscle model.
Hansol Ryu: Is there any questions so far before moving on to the closed space mechanics?
Hansol Ryu: I see something on the chat, let me see… Nope.
Hansol Ryu: Okay, no questions so far?
Hansol Ryu: Alright, let's talk about the PGLs a little bit.
Hansol Ryu: So, active muscle force actually comes from the closed glitch finding between thick filament and thin filament inside the muscle. On the left, we see the structure of the muscle. Muscles are bundled in multiple layers.
Hansol Ryu: But deep inside, there is, myofilaments, and there are actin and myosin filaments.
Hansol Ryu: And then in between them, there is a molecular binding called cosmits.
Hansol Ryu: And because the co-split cycles like this and pulls those filaments relative to each other, the muscle produces active force.
Hansol Ryu: And there are some passive elements around those myofilaments that also contribute to the overall force of the muscle, but those are passive forces.
Hansol Ryu: So active force comes from the closed splits, and passive force comes from other elements, and we can model that using CAH elastic elements, or parallel elastic elements on top of the closed split mechanics.
Hansol Ryu: So, how do we model close bridges?
Hansol Ryu: We will simplify it and say that cross-squared is basically a spring.
Hansol Ryu: That can pull those two filaments.
Hansol Ryu: And it, let's start with the simplest version, where there are two states. So, they can be either detached or out-touched, like this.
Hansol Ryu: And then within the muscle, there are so many, of the actin and myosin available.
Hansol Ryu: And they are at different lengths, and some of them are text, and some of them are detached.
Hansol Ryu: When you make a computational model of the muscle, we will count number of the artistical splits at each length.
Hansol Ryu: And then if we have the column to number,
Hansol Ryu: We can calculate how we'll have a transition next step.
Hansol Ryu: And there is, not a random transition, but there is an probabilistic model on how closely it will transition into another state, right? So…
Hansol Ryu: Here is the attachment rate and detachment rate, and you can see that they are the function of the close-grid links.
Hansol Ryu: So what it says is that, when you are near zero, you have a higher… highest probability of being attached.
Hansol Ryu: And then when you are pulled away from the wasting state.
Hansol Ryu: The probability of losing the connection, or getting detached increases.
Hansol Ryu: So, for example, let's say it's certain close-glitch links.
Hansol Ryu: There were 10 deep testicle switches, and you can come here and read the number on what is the attachment rate.
Hansol Ryu: And then multiply them to get how much co-speeds will get attached next to step.
Hansol Ryu: And same way, we can look at how much closed glitches are already out of text.
Hansol Ryu: and read…
Hansol Ryu: The detachment rate at that specific length, and see how much of the outtest close rates will lose the connection next to step.
Hansol Ryu: So, overall, we got 90 newly formed closed grids next to step.
Hansol Ryu: And you can do the same calculation for the all, available, close bridge lengths.
Hansol Ryu: And then let's calculate the transitional loads.
Hansol Ryu: Did it make sense so far? Any… pistons.
Hansol Ryu: Alright, we'll move on.
Hansol Ryu: So, we don't do it by… or by hand, but we do it by using a computational model like this.
Hansol Ryu: And once we get the distribution of the bound closed splits as a function of closed-split length, we can now calculate the ovular force as a summation of the splint forces.
Hansol Ryu: Which is proportional to the close-speed links.
Hansol Ryu: So the total force will become the summation of each closed weight force, for the bound close weight.
Hansol Ryu: And let me show you how it evolves over time.
Hansol Ryu: M.
Hansol Ryu: So, delicate. So, what's going on here is that… Hmm…
Hansol Ryu: All right, I'm trying to stop it a little bit quicker, but… alright, yeah. So, we were able to calculate the amount of bond cool splits at each length.
Hansol Ryu: And then pull the muscles, so the core splits are therapeutically pulled.
Hansol Ryu: towards the right. Alright, let me see if I can…
Hansol Ryu: Sorry, are we still looking at my screen?
Hansol Ryu: No? Fine. Alright, how about now?
Hansol Ryu: Or, like, cooked.
Hansol Ryu: So here, we… I'm sorry, you lost it.
Hansol Ryu: Or, like, bear with me, sorry, we'll come back. So here…
Hansol Ryu: The close split is at a steady state.
Hansol Ryu: And from the attachment rate and detachment rate, we get this much of a baseline attached cost split with this certain distribution.
Hansol Ryu: And when we start to pull the muscles, we can see that
Hansol Ryu: Pound cross-bits distribution shipped to the right world.
Hansol Ryu: That is because, close phrases that are already attached are physically pulled to the right.
Hansol Ryu: So, now the number of bound cross-bits is shifted to the right, but they cannot move, infinitely to the right, because they will start losing connection, because the detachment rate increases.
Hansol Ryu: As we go further away from the resting state.
Hansol Ryu: So if we keep pulling the muscle and increase the muscle length, this is what happens. Now, the height of the boundary decreased.
Hansol Ryu: Because Cosplay just started to lose… lose some connections.
Hansol Ryu: And then those close bridges that I detached and fled up can now enter the pool again at the resting length, and then start to bind again in the middle.
Hansol Ryu: So if we keep pulling and then keep the muscle there, we can see that
Hansol Ryu: Closed bound… number of bound close bits becomes centered at zero again.
Hansol Ryu: Alright, we'll go back to…
Hansol Ryu: Should I? Or… presentation.
Victoria Wood: What
Victoria Wood: We have a question in the chat I wanted to make sure, we addressed that. So, I had one question with what technique are you able to find out or look at the number of attached and detached cross bridges?
Hansol Ryu: Are we talking about the experimental methods?
Victoria Wood: Yes.
Hansol Ryu: Yes, our…
Hansol Ryu: Sorry, I do not know the answer. Is there anyone in the audience who can answer those? I'm more of a computational modeling person.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: I think you can't measure it. You fit the data… you… you adjust the detachment and attachment rates to fit the data. You can't measure it experimentally. This is a really complicated part of
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: Assemblages of molecular motors being one of the very toughest biophysical problems.
Hansol Ryu: Alright, thank you.
Hansol Ryu: I don't know, is there a way to look at the molecular procedure, actually, using some fancy microscopic technique?
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: You can measure for a single cross bridge using, like, an optical trap, or… Various other,
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: You know, methods, like, by physical nanoscale methods.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: But the problem is, then, it's only one crossbridge, it isn't an assembly.
Hansol Ryu: I see, okay.
Hansol Ryu: All right, thank you, Kiisa.
Hansol Ryu: Alright, so we are going to test out these, force development and how the shortening or lengthening affects number of bound close spreads using the GUI I will provide shortly.
Hansol Ryu: So, tedosta!
Hansol Ryu: explanation based on the simplest version of the closed splits model, but we can make the model a little more complicated by adding more states.
Hansol Ryu: So, so far, we said that closed bridges can be either in the oddest states or detached states, but there are experimental evidences that are suggesting that there could be other states that can explain the experimental observations.
Hansol Ryu: So…
Hansol Ryu: fully example, it is, suggested that the myosin can be in a super relaxed state, meaning that it is not ready to be bound.
Hansol Ryu: And,
Hansol Ryu: My ocean that is ready to be bound can transition into that super relaxed state by some… another… another rate functions.
Hansol Ryu: And also, what is important is that,
Hansol Ryu: It is not that our muscle fibers will just
Hansol Ryu: get attached constantly. It is modulated by the contour signal that is sent to the muscle. So muscle activation is sent to the muscle fiber as a form of calcium ion.
Hansol Ryu: And these calcium ions will enable those actins to be available for the binding. So…
Hansol Ryu: Only after getting the calcium binding, these actin sites become available and becomes ready to produce force.
Hansol Ryu: And this is how we,
Hansol Ryu: How we control our muscle model in the computational simulations.
Hansol Ryu: And this is how much, force is,
Hansol Ryu: Produced when you change the concentration of the calcium in the muscle filament in the model.
Hansol Ryu: The region we incorporate these extra states, depends pretty much on what kind of phenomena you want to, explain using the muscle model.
Hansol Ryu: And here we are showing the difference between basic model and two-states model, and this is because our team at Georgia Tech, Emily and Lubin, are interested in reproducing the
Hansol Ryu: He's totally dependent property of the muscle going through this series of stretches, and then we are interested about reproducing these, subtle differences in the first development.
Hansol Ryu: But depending on your problem, you may not need the three-stage model.
Hansol Ryu: Or you may need 5-state model, right? So it all depends.
Hansol Ryu: All right, so let's test it out using the code
Hansol Ryu: I shared. Victoria, as you already sent out the GitHub page, but if you haven't downloaded it yet.
Hansol Ryu: please, get it from the GitHub.
Hansol Ryu: Just letting you know, this is the code we used to provide the tutorial at ISB, International Society for Biomechanics, meeting.
Hansol Ryu: last year, titled Musculoskeletor Simulations with Biopical Muscle Models, which we did with Lina, Serbi, Kim, and Fluido. And Serbi and Tim, contributed a lot for making this possible.
Hansol Ryu: So, how are people doing with getting the…
Hansol Ryu: code. Can I have dumb job if people downloaded the code?
Hansol Ryu: Right?
Hansol Ryu: Were people able to run it? Let's see.
Hansol Ryu: Now I will share a different screen so that we can try it out.
Hansol Ryu: Right? Did people, unzip what they downloaded?
Hansol Ryu: Alright?
Hansol Ryu: Olivia, would you like to sit with me and see?
Hansol Ryu: Or then, in the cold…
Hansol Ryu: There are several folders like this, Common Parts 1 and 2, and we are going to go into Part 1,
Hansol Ryu: and tutorial.
Hansol Ryu: Can I get thumbs up if people are here?
Hansol Ryu: Alright? And let's open GUI, prosperidsNhill.m file.
Hansol Ryu: Alright?
Hansol Ryu: And then you can simply run it.
Hansol Ryu: It may take some time, but…
Hansol Ryu: Right.
Hansol Ryu: Are we looking at my figure together, or is it not shared?
Victoria Wood: Yeah, we can see your figure.
Hansol Ryu: Alright.
Hansol Ryu: Alright, this is the GUID to play with our cross-grid model.
Hansol Ryu: Let me tell you some features.
Hansol Ryu: So here are the parameters that are…
Hansol Ryu: specifying the attachment and detachment rates, and I will go into more details, shortly.
Hansol Ryu: But yeah, that's the control panel to,
Hansol Ryu: change the attachment and detachment rates. And here is the… oh, you're not saying it, sorry. Here is the…
Hansol Ryu: Muscle lengths over time on the x-axis.
Hansol Ryu: And then here is the activation PCA on the y-axis here.
Hansol Ryu: And then on the bottom grip, we see how much force is developed from the model.
Hansol Ryu: And you can click anywhere here.
Hansol Ryu: To go do the time.
Hansol Ryu: And see how much co-split is formed on the bottom left corner.
Hansol Ryu: Do people get it?
Hansol Ryu: Right? Does it run on everyone's laptops?
Hansol Ryu: All right, now let's simulate shortening. So you can click here on the protocurve.
Hansol Ryu: And then make it to shortening.
Hansol Ryu: And then click run.
Hansol Ryu: It will tell you to wait a little bit.
Hansol Ryu: And then generate the forest.
Hansol Ryu: Is it working for everybody so far?
Hansol Ryu: And we can even test the lengthening cycle like this.
Hansol Ryu: And as I told you earlier.
Hansol Ryu: Even though this lengthening looks same as this lengthening.
Hansol Ryu: We see different amount of force developed here, between here and here.
Hansol Ryu: And… does anyone have an explanation of why we have a different amount of force?
Hansol Ryu: using this GUI,
Hansol Ryu: All right, any guess on why the recessive font?
Victoria Wood: Is it the history?
Hansol Ryu: Yep.
Victoria Wood: That's leading up to it?
Hansol Ryu: So let me clarify that we are actually not modeling the history explicitly.
Hansol Ryu: But we are just keeping track of how much cosmoid is found in the muscle.
Hansol Ryu: And because…
Hansol Ryu: When you reach this point at time, that is how much core split you had in your muscle.
Hansol Ryu: But if you went through lengthening and shortening.
Hansol Ryu: And came to this point in time, there are a different amount of close reads obtained in your muscle compared to here and here.
Hansol Ryu: And because of that, our muscle model has a history-dependent property as an emerging property, rather than we explicitly kept track of the history of everything.
Hansol Ryu: Didn't make sense?
Hansol Ryu: Alright, cool.
Hansol Ryu: Now, let me show you what we can do with the attachment rate and detachment rate. Our…
Hansol Ryu: Oh, well, let me just stay in this window. So, here is the attachment rate on the second row of the left column.
Hansol Ryu: And F and W's are the parameters we used to characterize this curve.
Hansol Ryu: So you can play with it, so if you…
Hansol Ryu: lower the app, you can see the height of the attachment range changing.
Hansol Ryu: And then by moving W, you can…
Hansol Ryu: Change the width of the test month curve.
Hansol Ryu: And you can see that all the forces disappeared once you changed the property of the muscle.
Hansol Ryu: And after setting up the parameters, You can click run, again.
Hansol Ryu: to generate the force using the muscle you just created now. And we can see changing forces here.
Hansol Ryu: And here comes our, black loom activity.
Hansol Ryu: Give me a second. Where's my…
Hansol Ryu: Oh, no, my PowerPoint wants to crash, just give me a second. Any questions, anyone?
Hansol Ryu: While I restart my PowerPoint?
Chastain, Maddy: When you change F and W, does it change, like, the history of the…
Chastain, Maddy: I forgot what the, like, little graph was called, but does it change the history of that as well?
Hansol Ryu: No, I didn't.
Hansol Ryu: Or we will… we are going to simulate it from the beginning.
Hansol Ryu: So…
Hansol Ryu: When it reaches the steady state, depending on your muscle properties, your muscle may have a different amount of cross-buence of text.
Hansol Ryu: At the resting state, but not that we are actually keeping it in the history.
Hansol Ryu: Oh.
Chastain, Maddy: Okay, that makes sense.
Hansol Ryu: Right.
Victoria Wood: We've got another question here in the chat. Amulya asks, so the main history that this model is tracking is the amount of attachments that it had at the start. Is that correct?
Hansol Ryu: Yes.
Hansol Ryu: Okay, cool.
Victoria Wood: Thank you.
Hansol Ryu: Alright, thank you.
Hansol Ryu: Oh yeah, found it.
Hansol Ryu: Alright, so, now… I'm going to ask Etolia to…
Hansol Ryu: put people into playrooms so that we can try out different attachment and detachment traits.
Hansol Ryu: And this is what we are going to do. Each team will decide on what they want to change on the attachment rate and detachment rate, and then they will discuss what they expect to see.
Hansol Ryu: And then run the simulation and see
Hansol Ryu: How steady-state cross-built distribution changed, and how much, and how the force changed.
Hansol Ryu: And confirm whether it matches your expectation.
Hansol Ryu: And here are some suggested changes that you can make.
Hansol Ryu: You can see… well, it's the… oh.
Hansol Ryu: Effect of the lower attachment rate by changing the F parameter.
Hansol Ryu: Here.
Hansol Ryu: Or you can also try to make it really sharp by decreasing the W parameter a lot, or you can make it really wide and see what happens.
Hansol Ryu: Or, you can actually make the determinant rate go really low on either side by,
Hansol Ryu: lower link K12 and K22 parameters.
Hansol Ryu: Or I make it go up, or I make only one side go down and see what happens.
Hansol Ryu: So, make some predictions on what you are going to see, and then play with the model, and see if
Hansol Ryu: Close-bridge distribution and force as a leader to it matches your expectations during the steady state and during the shortening and lengthening, and then please share your team's Valavie case when we are done with it.
Hansol Ryu: Let's take 10 minutes on it.
Victoria Wood: Alright, so I have breakout rooms pretty much set. One quick question, the CHP233D, are you guys a breakout, or a watch party, or is that a single person?
Victoria Wood: a particular.
CHP233d: Thanks so much party.
Victoria Wood: Okay, I'll move you to your own room then.
Victoria Wood: Okay, I put WATCHP parties in your own breakout rooms so you guys can, just collaborate locally, but if anybody in here is in the same room as a watch party and doesn't want to be in a separate breakout room, just stay in the main room, don't join your breakout room.
Victoria Wood: Break out… Got a lot of watch parties.
Victoria Wood: Rachel, is there… a different watch party, I should… Add you to…
Victoria Wood: Mmm…
Victoria Wood: We have rooms 1 and 4 are very small, so I'm actually gonna go and I'm gonna combine them.
Victoria Wood: Alright, that should be good. Each room has at least 3 people. Are you okay with that?
Hansol Ryu: Bobby, what did you say?
Victoria Wood: Just, each room has… 3… a minimum of three… three to four people. Is that good?
Victoria Wood: Cool.
Hansol Ryu: I don't know how many… I mean, how many teams we are going to hear from.
Hansol Ryu: But yeah, I see. So how many tweak columns did we end up getting?
Victoria Wood: We ended up getting, because we have 6 watch parties today. We have, we have, 9 rooms, room 1 and… and we have 10 rooms. Room 1 ended up being empty, so… 9 rooms.
Hansol Ryu: Oh, wow. Alright, that's a lot.
Victoria Wood: Sorry, hopefully that doesn't take, take too much time for people to contribute after.
Hansol Ryu: But, yeah, it'll be fun.
Amulya Kadaba: Hi! Sorry, all of us in the breakout room actually weren't able to run the code, so…
Amulya Kadaba: come back, and then maybe, be put into different rooms, because I actually don't have MATLAB, so… so I was having troubles.
Victoria Wood: Sure. Okay, I will move you to room 2.
Victoria Wood: Aaron Matthews… I'll move you to… Room 4…
Victoria Wood: Mmm… No.
Victoria Wood: Your heater rooms here as well…
Victoria Wood: Thank Ki Sir, I'll move you.
Victoria Wood: Which one has fewer?
Victoria Wood: Advanced students?
Victoria Wood: I do.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: I did run the code at the conference workshop, but I didn't have time to get it to just… I didn't have the time to set it up this morning.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: So, sorry about that.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: I thought I could…
Hansol Ryu: Joining again?
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: Yeah, I thought I could help with predictions, so okay. I'll see you guys later.
Victoria Wood: Sounds good.
Victoria Wood: Alright, now we have… 8 rooms. Just 2 virtual rooms, and the rest are all watch parties.
Hansol Ryu: Well, I wish that it means that our other looms were able to run it, at least 1% alone.
Victoria Wood: Hopefully, yeah.
Victoria Wood: Some of these WATCH parties are really big, so I think… I think somebody will have been able to.
Hansol Ryu: Right.
Hansol Ryu: Wow, thank you for giving.
Victoria Wood: Yeah, of course! Watch parties, or the breakout rooms always end up… they're so useful, because it actually gets people engaged and involved, but it always is annoying.
Hansol Ryu: Right, yeah.
Hansol Ryu: Oh, oof.
Hansol Ryu: Wow, there are so many switchings between programs for me today, so…
Victoria Wood: Busy, busy time of year.
Hansol Ryu: Oh, sorry, I mean, do you think this workshopizes.
Victoria Wood: Oh.
Hansol Ryu: We need to switch a lot between, you know, PowerPoint and Medline.
Victoria Wood: You're doing great.
Hansol Ryu: Oh, yeah, it's been too.
Victoria Wood: Looks mood so far.
Hansol Ryu: Thank you. Everyone is being so patient with me.
Hansol Ryu: Okay, working out for you?
Victoria Wood: Hey, Monica, we're just in breakout rooms right now. I don't know if you want to join one or not.
Monica Daley (she, her): Yeah, my internet connection is a bit dodgy, so I'm not… I'm probably not going to be able to do the interactive stuff very effectively right now.
Victoria Wood: That's fine.
Monica Daley (she, her): How are you doing?
Victoria Wood: Pretty good.
Victoria Wood: Not so bad.
Victoria Wood: Are you keeping track, Hansol, of the time for this breakout room, or was I supposed to be keeping track?
Hansol Ryu: I didn't really take care of it. It has been, like, Little over 5 minutes, isn't?
Victoria Wood: Yeah, sure.
Hansol Ryu: Let's give people maybe 3 more minutes.
Victoria Wood: Okay, I'll send out a one-minute warning in, like, 2 minutes.
Victoria Wood: Or I'll just send out a warning now.
Victoria Wood: 3-minute warning.
Hansol Ryu: Does it work better if we designate who is going to share their… Wizards.
Hansol Ryu: Or can we just tell people to volunteer?
Victoria Wood: I can broadcast a message that, if you want me to tell each group to, like, pick somebody to be ready to share, does that… does that work?
Hansol Ryu: Yep, let's third, yeah.
Victoria Wood: Alright, I'm gonna go ahead and close the rooms so they'll have, 60 seconds to come back.
Katrina Moore: Camera's off.
Victoria Wood: Alright, everybody should be back from breakout rooms.
Hansol Ryu: Alright, welcome back, everybody!
Hansol Ryu: coffee platform.
Hansol Ryu: Can we now see…
Hansol Ryu: What kind of predictions people had, and what kind of observations they had, and whether it makes sense.
Hansol Ryu: Compared to their predictions.
Hansol Ryu: Yeah.
Victoria Wood: Yeah, we can maybe start with room 2. A couple of our rooms ended up being empty. So room 1's empty, room 2, that had Amulya, Casey, Kiisa, they're a room.
Casey King: Perfect. So I said I would speak for our room. So we started with, basically just a couple basic predictions. So we thought that if we increased the attachment rate, so I think that's that F parameter.
Casey King: We expected to see a larger peak force from the crossbridge, force production, and we verified it, and that…
Casey King: we were right about that. And then, when we, we also predicted that, some…
Casey King: combination of these K parameters, which are the cooperativity parameters and something else.
Casey King: the… if we offset them, so if we made the K1s
Casey King: high, and the K2s low, then we would see an increase in force.
Casey King: well, actually, some offset of them would create, like, a maximum production of force, but we weren't quite sure what combination of those parameters would produce the highest force. So, that was something that we just decided to experiment with. That's what our group did.
Hansol Ryu: Oh, thank you for sharing!
Hansol Ryu: I would guess that maybe that also depends on what kind of lengthening or shortening you do.
Hansol Ryu: So, a combination of K1221 and those things will make your detachment curve skewed.
Hansol Ryu: And then, if you are going towards that way, and then make the curve lower that point, closed splits will be less likely to lose their binding, and will be able to pull this larger force. But if you pull it the other way around, you may actually lose more closed splits.
Casey King: Right, and that was something that we probably should have changed a little bit more. We kept the protocol as, like, a lengthening cycle the whole time, so we probably should have
Casey King: Switched it to a shortening cycle to see, what those parameters would lead to.
Hansol Ryu: Cool, thank you.
Hansol Ryu: Renee, can you hear from the next scoop?
Victoria Wood: Alright, so next group would be room for, so Andrew Thornton, Maddy Chastain, your group.
Victoria Wood: So I'll have Katrina, Aaron, and Mane as well.
Chastain, Maddy: I can talk for us. So we kind of just, like, explored a little.
Chastain, Maddy: But also, one of us, like.
Chastain, Maddy: like, put all of them, the, parameters at the highest setting, kind of broke the program a little bit, and then at the lowest setting, and broke it again. And then in the middle, and we noticed that it was, like.
Chastain, Maddy: It had, like, a…
Chastain, Maddy: like, I did the PCA, I put all the parameters in the middle, and then I put the PCA at the lowest.
Chastain, Maddy: And, I noticed that it was, like, a straight line, and then it, plateaued for, I believe.
Chastain, Maddy: The… hell… no. The…
Chastain, Maddy: Hill coefficient, I think that was what it was. And then for the crossbidge cycles, it was just, like.
Chastain, Maddy: Like, a box square, where for the,
Chastain, Maddy: if you put it at, like, a higher PCA, or a low, like, a higher calcium concentration, was more of a irregular shape than you saw.
Chastain, Maddy: more, like, different… Like, how you saw it, and like, when you, like, just hit with the,
Chastain, Maddy: regular, like, controls, so that was interesting to see at the different PCA levels.
Hansol Ryu: Cool, yeah, thank you for sharing. I think it is also experimentally known that
Hansol Ryu: the short change stiffness property, which is the sudden inclusion force if you stretch the muscle really suddenly. The effect is more prominent on, in the submaximal activation level.
Hansol Ryu: So your activation is too low or too high, you don't actually see it too much, but there's some interesting point in the middle. And probably that is where actual muscles are oculating in most of the cases. So, yeah, that's really a fun thing to observe.
Hansol Ryu: Ray, can you hear from the next group?
Victoria Wood: Right, I think USC messaged me they had some… some… some errors with their code, so we might have to work on that separately.
Victoria Wood: Uci watch party next?
Victoria Wood: Okay.
Victoria Wood: Let's… and then mine's doing late. The Emory Watch Party. Did you guys… were you guys able to… to run the code?
Emory Watch Party: Yes,
Emory Watch Party: Yes, we, we mainly kept every, the parameters the same. The thing we mostly played with was the PCA level and, the protocol in the short end, and LinkedIn,
Emory Watch Party: States, and we observed that, when it was in the shortened protocol, the force produced was less than
Emory Watch Party: the LinkedIn protocol when PCA was both high and low, right?
Emory Watch Party: Yes.
Emory Watch Party: like Hansol was saying, it depends on the state.
Hansol Ryu: Alright, thank you.
Victoria Wood: It's, CHP233D, I have no idea which watch party you are. But if you have anything to share…
CHP233d: Hi, sorry, I guess, we couldn't change the name of the room.
CHP233d: Good.
CHP233d: So we just,
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): Can you hear me okay?
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): Okay.
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): Perfect. So, we just, made, the attachment rate to be zero completely.
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): And, ran the simulation for shortening, as well as, lengthening.
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): So, I guess what we found was, even though… so basically, design between data 0, the distribution of one was more or less the same.
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): For shortening, the force reduced, and for lengthening, the force increased.
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): So, we thought it mostly remains the same. Maybe it is due to the Basel?
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): Elements, or am I… I'm just… just wondering, we are missing… are we missing something there?
Hansol Ryu: Sorry, I didn't hear the first part really clearly, but did you say that you…
Hansol Ryu: Put everything zero and still saw some force developing.
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): Yeah, yeah.
Hansol Ryu: You're right, there are some passive elements, so yeah, even without the close glitch, it will generate some force.
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): Okay, that's for lengthening, but why is the force decreasing for shortening?
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): Even though the attachment… the amount of attachment remains the same?
Hansol Ryu: That, I don't really know, I will need to look into it. But it can be some weird infection with the passive elements again, but yeah.
Hansol Ryu: That's… I mean, I think the way… well, it was actually Tim implemented those elements, so I will blame Tim if it is wrong, but I think the, it is set such a way that even during the resting.
Hansol Ryu: the… The passive elements are under some tension.
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): I see, I see.
Hansol Ryu: So, shortening would still do something, but yeah, sorry, I'm not super clear about it, so…
Hansol Ryu: Thank you, and I didn't know that, so I will look into that.
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): So, thanks.
Victoria Wood: Alright, that's the last of our groups.
Hansol Ryu: Cool. All right, I hope people had fun simulating Hormu motives.
Hansol Ryu: So let me briefly talk about other features of our model.
Hansol Ryu: So, in the beginning, I told people that there is force length and force velocity relationship in the muscles, and our model is able to simulate that.
Hansol Ryu: So for conventional huge time muscle models, usually those muscle models will start with a place-clived force length and force velocity curve.
Hansol Ryu: and then multiply those together to estimate the force at a certain length and velocity. But for our model, when you simulate the model at a different length or a different…
Hansol Ryu: Valencia, you can see how much force it's developed.
Hansol Ryu: And then plot it over length and velocity to get this typical force length and velocity curve.
Hansol Ryu: So, I will show how to do this, right.
Hansol Ryu: One more screen.
Hansol Ryu: Switching… Ready to go. Sure.
Hansol Ryu: So many things open.
Hansol Ryu: All right, yeah, here's our program again, and people can try that on their laptop if they like.
Hansol Ryu: You can see that actually there was a hill curve on top of the blue curve here on the first curve, and that one I…
Hansol Ryu: already had some default values for the Hill Time Muscle Model, for this, my default parameters. And you can see that Hill Time Muscle Model
Hansol Ryu: Estimate the force…
Hansol Ryu: kind of similar to the cost-bits model. So overall, it simulates a similar amount of force, but the transient is where the difference is.
Hansol Ryu: But when you start changing the master properties, let me just reduce the attachment rate, because that is the most…
Hansol Ryu: straightforward thing to see. So now the probability of close breeds being a test is reduced.
Hansol Ryu: And because of that, we get overall less force.
Hansol Ryu: But the hill time muscle model didn't update yet, so it is not, estimating the force correctly.
Hansol Ryu: So now we can generate the hill type curve using these new parameters by clicking generate the hill button.
Hansol Ryu: So when you click it, what it does is that it will simulate the co-speed force at multiple muscle lengths.
Hansol Ryu: And simulate the isometric force. So, you are seeing the force on the graphic here.
Hansol Ryu: And then also, it will simulate the force velocity curve by pulling the muscle at different velocities.
Hansol Ryu: But we really evaluate the force when,
Hansol Ryu: Each of the muscles are going through the same lengths.
Hansol Ryu: So, for the ZVO velocity, we will look at the isometric force for the lengthening cycle, we will start with a slightly shorter muscle and pull it at a constant velocity, and see what is the force when it comes to the same length.
Hansol Ryu: So, by running multiple simulations at different, lengths, velocity, and PCA level, these are the curves we get. First things, velocity and PCA curves. I think those spikes happens because of
Hansol Ryu: Having too low a pitchman rate, and the numerical method sometimes becomes a little bit weird at too low or too high, values.
Hansol Ryu: But yeah, that is how we can generate the hue-type curve.
Hansol Ryu: are the first thing's force velocity curves out of our close-speeds muscle model. And now you can see that field-time muscle model, predicts similar amount of force as our closed speeds model.
Hansol Ryu: And now we have this new Hiltheim muscle model. We can simulate different types of protocols.
Hansol Ryu: and compare how he can also model and close-grid's muscle model.
Hansol Ryu: Estimates muscle force stiff only.
Hansol Ryu: I would say, overall, they are similar, but depending on your question that you are asking, if this transient matters for you.
Hansol Ryu: maybe you need a close-riched muscle model other than using his time muscle model, but if you are looking for, say.
Hansol Ryu: Evil is forced at steady state. Maybe his time muscle model will be not for you.
Hansol Ryu: Any questions on this? Can people try their own hill tire muscle models?
Hansol Ryu: I will give you maybe a couple of minutes.
Hansol Ryu: And please put thumbs up when you're done with it.
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): Hansol, I have a question.
Hansol Ryu: Okay.
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): So having people tried to modify this hill-type muscle model, like, add some history-dependent property, like length rate.
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): or some kind of additional elements, because I think people have access to a lot of experimental data, right?
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): Like, can they improvised… I mean, have people looked at that already, or not?
Hansol Ryu: Haha, that is actually coming next in my presentation.
Hansol Ryu: So yeah, there has been some attempts to incorporate history dependence into Hilton muscle, but so far, they are limited for different reasons.
Hansol Ryu: So, I will talk about that a little more later, but the main problem is generalizability.
Hansol Ryu: So, the way they… please, Clive, the short transition stiffness needs to be dependent on what kind of
Hansol Ryu: movement happened before, or how much… how much movement is going to happen during your stretches and things like that. I will…
Hansol Ryu: Tell you more with the example later, though.
Hansol Ryu: Alright, can I get thumbs up if people were able to generate their real-time master model?
Hansol Ryu: Right, thanks.
Hansol Ryu: Right.
Hansol Ryu: Stop share, I'm going back to my… presentation again.
Hansol Ryu: Right, so…
Hansol Ryu: Yeah, that was the basics of how our muscle model works, and let me tell you more about what it means for our understanding of the biological movement.
Hansol Ryu: So I will tell you a little more about what I'm doing with these muscle models, and hopefully they will answer some of the questions you may have, like what I just got.
Hansol Ryu: So, when you look at people's response, when we perturb them on a perturbation platform like this.
Hansol Ryu: their joint torque.
Hansol Ryu: Are specific to the joint.
Hansol Ryu: So typically, we see much faster increase on the joint torque on the hip joint, and then it'll go down sooner, and then when the platform decelerates.
Hansol Ryu: We see the dip to the opposite side.
Hansol Ryu: And then it is a little more smooth in the knee, and then on the ankle, the force develops much more slowly, and then stays on the same side, and it doesn't quite go back to the other side.
Hansol Ryu: So, if we want to use a muscle model to study the mechanism, and want to answer questions like why different joints have different torque properties.
Hansol Ryu: We may need a muscle model, but let me just show you that hillside muscle model is not quite suitable for answering these questions.
Hansol Ryu: This is another data from the human experiment.
Hansol Ryu: And here is what happens with the conventional histone muscle model during the 100 milliseconds after the perturbation.
Hansol Ryu: So 100 milliseconds is quite short. It is shorter than time that is typically needed for the feedback test rays to generate torque because of the delay in the neuromuscular system.
Hansol Ryu: And on the left.
Hansol Ryu: is what we measured from humans, and you see fairly little movement, right? It… it barely moves.
Hansol Ryu: And on the middle is the simulation lizard using conventional heat type muscle model.
Hansol Ryu: And then you see that it overestimates the initial movement by a large amount.
Hansol Ryu: And if we get that much urban defense in the initial movement.
Hansol Ryu: That may also lead us to a missing interpretation of how much collective talk is needed later to collect this error, position error.
Hansol Ryu: And the previous authors, Degreta Attar, showed that they can place Clive's short-changes stiffness.
Hansol Ryu: like… the, like, the question I just got.
Hansol Ryu: They get much better lizards, so… The, simulation lizard looks
Hansol Ryu: More like the experimental lizard, so showing that it is actually needed
Hansol Ryu: To have the short-range stiffness in your muscle properties.
Hansol Ryu: But how they did it was by preciping the short range stiffness. So they said.
Hansol Ryu: Well, I'm slightly unclear whether it was time-dependent or length-dependent.
Hansol Ryu: But for this type of simulation, they should mean actually the same thing, that… so…
Hansol Ryu: During the initial stretch, they said, have higher torque, or a higher stiffness on your joint, on your muscles.
Hansol Ryu: But the problem of doing so was that it was not generalizable.
Hansol Ryu: So, when they test the model against a different direction of the perturbation, or when they perturb the model by a different amplitude.
Hansol Ryu: The amount of short-range stiffness they needed to reproduce human data was different, meaning if they fixed one type of short-range stiffness, it wouldn't generate to a close multiple experimental conditions.
Hansol Ryu: And…
Hansol Ryu: If the short-changes stiffness emerges from the muscle model we have that is based on the paleological process of the muscle, we are hoping that it is more generalizable, and thus we can use it to simulate,
Hansol Ryu: balanced response better than heal time muscle is. Did it now answer your question?
Hansol Ryu: What's your freedom, by the way?
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): Yes.
Hansol Ryu: Yep.
Hansol Ryu: Any questions, I suppose, returning to stiffness?
Hansol Ryu: Alright, moving on.
Hansol Ryu: So, the GUI you played with.
Hansol Ryu: We're showing the case where we impose the movement. That is similar to how we do the experiment on the muscle fibers, or muscle in the lab, when you have isolated muscle, and you pull it to the length you desire.
Hansol Ryu: So the lens was, imposed to the muscle, but the other way of running close bridge simulation is by coupling it with other dynamic systems like this.
Hansol Ryu: And then the simulation needs to meet the constraint that the overall length change of the muscle
Hansol Ryu: On both sides should met the change in the angle of this inverted pendulum.
Hansol Ryu: And again, there is co-spread muscle mechanics inside this muscle model.
Hansol Ryu: And we can apply perturbation.
Hansol Ryu: Or…
Hansol Ryu: and come up with a contour loop like this. There is the dynamics of the segment. Here, it is the embedded pendulum.
Hansol Ryu: And then deadline and muscles are connected by the length constraint.
Hansol Ryu: And then we can now run optimization studies on asking things like, what is the optimal excitation pattern, or what is the optimal balancing strategy if you have a system like this.
Hansol Ryu: By applying the default amount of calcium agent control signal to the muscle.
Hansol Ryu: And we can also test the effect of variable tendon compliance.
Hansol Ryu: By connecting our cross-bits muscle model to tendons of different compliances.
Hansol Ryu: Because it is fun to look at. Let me just show some of my results.
Hansol Ryu: So, this is how much force is developed when you simulate your muscle, like what you just did.
Hansol Ryu: But if we simulate the same muscle model with a more compliant tendon attached to it.
Hansol Ryu: Even when the ovular lengths change.
Hansol Ryu: to the muscle-tendon unit is the same. We can see the blue bar moving Together for these two muscles.
Hansol Ryu: Because when you have a compliant tendon, compliant tendon will observe some of the displacement that is imposed from outside.
Hansol Ryu: The contractor element shown in pink here is going… is experiencing much less length change compared to the stiff tendon.
Hansol Ryu: And you can run the closed space simulation inside the muscle to see how much force is developed.
Hansol Ryu: And because the compliant tendon will observe the displacement, and the muscle fiber doesn't go through a lot of length chains.
Hansol Ryu: The amount of stiffness it develops is reduced when you have more compliant tendon.
Hansol Ryu: And if you put that back into the inverted pendulum dynamics.
Hansol Ryu: This is what happens with our simulation. So, because the hip muscles are connected to a much more stiff tendon.
Hansol Ryu: Our simulation will show that, okay, the, joint torque
Hansol Ryu: That is connected to the more stiff tendon will increase much more sharply, where joint torque connected to a compliant tendon will increase really slowly, like this.
Hansol Ryu: And then we can do the optimization on the flip again to, simulate the overall control response.
Hansol Ryu: And our simulation captures most of the key trends seen in human data across the front joint, like this.
Hansol Ryu: So, actually, that is the end of my presentation, and…
Hansol Ryu: I will show the sign-in link again in case some people missed it.
Hansol Ryu: And feel free to stay for more discussions, or feel free to leave if you need to go. And thank you for joining today!
Hansol Ryu: Oh, and by the way, there is part 2 in the code you downloaded from the GitHub, and if you are interested in simulating something like this, like the inverted pendulum, there is the code in the Part 2 custom.
Hansol Ryu: If you want to try it. And let me know if you have any questions about it.
Victoria Wood: Thanks so much, Hansol.
Hansol Ryu: Thank you.
Victoria Wood: I know we had a few people, a few groups too, that had some trouble with, running the code. This would be a good chance, to ask any questions about any of the, errors you might have received.
Hansol Ryu: Yeah, was it that you didn't have MetLive, or…
Hansol Ryu: Did the code run error?
Hansol Ryu: Can I learn more about it?
USC IAS Watch Party: Hello?
Hansol Ryu: Hello!
USC IAS Watch Party: Hi, yeah, we were having trouble running the code, but we figured out that it was the way it was saving to our computers. I guess we had to change the…
USC IAS Watch Party: The folder, like, The place it was saved, for it to run?
USC IAS Watch Party: But we decided to get it to rent, so… the GUI.
USC IAS Watch Party: Thank you.
Hansol Ryu: Alright?
Hansol Ryu: Yeah, I think you will need to be in the folder, and probably maybe try to add other subfolders to the net test, if that helps.
Victoria Wood: I wonder if it needs to be out of the downloads folder.
Hansol Ryu: I'm like, Kisa?
USC IAS Watch Party: Oh, sorry. I sent up the folder first, and then, like, export it, and then move it around.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: MATLAB is very fussy about where things are, so that is always the first thing to check when your code doesn't run.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: Hansol, I had a… I had a more of a science question, maybe, while other people think about coding questions.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: And that is… so you had the… the nice prediction from your model that, tendon compliance could be responsible for the different responses of… at the different joints to perturbations.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: But have you gone back to the literature to see whether that hypothesis is supported by data on the compliance of the different tendons at the different joints?
Hansol Ryu: I've looked at some, yeah, tendon compliance from the literature, and so far it seems like so. Like, Achilles tendon is really compliant.
Hansol Ryu: And the tendons on the joint around the knee are a little less compliant, but still kind of compliant.
Hansol Ryu: Where it seems like the muscles connected to hip joints are most… Steve.
Hansol Ryu: But I looked at, yeah, a few muscles that were along the joint.
Hansol Ryu: Seems like, yeah, so far there is some gradient across those joints.
Hansol Ryu: And I wonder whether it actually means something for the function of the joint, proximal to this tear.
Hansol Ryu: And I think there also is a suggestion that achilles tendon stiffness is maybe optimal for the…
Hansol Ryu: Frequency of our walking and running.
Hansol Ryu: For the optimal energy return.
Hansol Ryu: So, it might be a…
Hansol Ryu: Yeah, compliant tendon might be a feature that is helpful for the energy, but maybe hurts a little bit in terms of balance, if it slows down the logistic torque development.
Hansol Ryu: Do you have any thoughts?
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: Well, I was just thinking that just all other things equal, which of course they aren't, of course the tendons are longer in the distal limb, and
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: Of course, if you have just a longer spring with the same properties, it's going to be more compliant.
Hansol Ryu: Okay.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: So it partly could be, like, there could be, like, this anatomical…
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: constraint that actually is somewhat adaptive as well. Does that make sense?
Hansol Ryu: Yes, yes.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: Yes, yes.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: Yeah, nice work.
Hansol Ryu: Thank you.
Hansol Ryu: Any other science questions or anything?
Amulya Kadaba: I had a question. So, I'm very new to all of this, and so one of the questions that I had was.
Amulya Kadaba: I'm currently working on very experimental work, so I don't really understand too much about the computational, but how do you come up with the numbers for the attachment rate and detachment rate and the number of attached cross bridges if you can't experimentally see them?
Hansol Ryu: Okay, that part was largely done by my colleagues Tim Van Dilce and Sury Bishima, but, I know that some of those comes from the, experiment.
Hansol Ryu: So you…
Hansol Ryu: what is the, like, natural attachment and detachment traits. I think some of them, actually, you can check to the molecular to assess.
Hansol Ryu: And some of the, rates…
Hansol Ryu: They fit the model to a single fiber experimental data.
Amulya Kadaba: Oh, okay.
Hansol Ryu: So, yeah, fit the data to the single fiber data, and then use that model to predict the behavior of the data later.
Amulya Kadaba: Okay, that makes sense. Thank you.
Hansol Ryu: Yeah, I think some of those parameters are somewhat bound to physics or chemistry.
Hansol Ryu: Where some of those are more of an effect of an overall muscle structure, and is different across species, or different across muscle types.
Hansol Ryu: So, I think TMSRV did a good work of looking into the literatures to see, you know, what are numbers they can just get from some
Hansol Ryu: P6 parameters, or physics particle is constants.
Hansol Ryu: And some of them, they fitted, yeah, to the single fiber experiment.
Amulya Kadaba: Okay, thank you.
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): Hi, Hansol, very nice talk. I was just wondering, what are the next steps for this model? Are you guys thinking about implementing in the multi-muscle, like, lower extremity task? And then the second question is, how, intensive is the computations? Can we, like, how, how do you…
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): I think it's gonna pan out. Yeah, I'm just curious.
Hansol Ryu: All right, thanks for the questions. For the model next step, there are multiple ways we can go. One of them would be doing maybe double inverted pendulum, rather than doing single inverted pendulum, because obviously those lower limb joints intact with each other.
Hansol Ryu: Oh, that is one thing. Other thing we can…
Hansol Ryu: Extend the model to have a more realistic energy model?
Hansol Ryu: Because this model is based on the molecular process within the muscle, and we know, like, how much ATP is needed for those switches to bind and things like that.
Hansol Ryu: Probably we can have a better model of energy of the muscle.
Hansol Ryu: And maybe can use that to run the optimization on the… Trade-offs in biological controls.
Hansol Ryu: I am interested in the control aspect of it, so I'm making the feedback loops and optimizing it and seeing how it changes when there are changes in the system, like when you have some disease condition.
Hansol Ryu: And have increased delay, increased noise, or maybe some wiring between the sensor loops get a bit altered. What is the effect a bit, and what are the adaptation strategies, given those conditions.
Hansol Ryu: What was the second question? Sorry.
Hansol Ryu: Computational time?
Speaker 1 (CHP233d): Yeah, so if, suppose if you're using it in a, like, a whole body simulation, can we replace it with the hill-type muscle model and, do competitions, do forward simulations, and so on? Like, are you guys thinking along that lines?
Hansol Ryu: I don't have an exact number at hand right now, but, cost-breach simulation is computationally more expensive than the hilt-time master model, that is for sure. So…
Hansol Ryu: There has been some efforts made to make it more efficient.
Hansol Ryu: So, rather than, say, keep track of the overall distribution.
Hansol Ryu: of the Bound Core Squids, team and Flidel, aka you Luven, are working on the…
Hansol Ryu: Alright, I'm blacking out the name, but direct moment model. So by…
Hansol Ryu: approximating the cross-squit distribution to a Gaussian distribution, they can come up with a mathematical equation of the, like, moment of the distribution, first moment, second moment of the distribution, to calculate the, force.
Hansol Ryu: More easily, and then they can simplify the trend…
Hansol Ryu: transition equation by doing so. So they can calculate the transition of the lower Gaussian distribution into another Gaussian distribution, rather than evaluating transition at each point on the distribution. And by doing so, they were able to make it more
Hansol Ryu: computationally efficient.
Hansol Ryu: So…
Hansol Ryu: From my experience of working with the model, it seems like running the direct method, so without the approximation of the distribution.
Hansol Ryu: I think, close blitz takes, like, 10 times longer than the Hilltime muscle model for my simulation.
Hansol Ryu: And with the approximation model, it seems like it is around, like, twice or three times longer.
Hansol Ryu: So are you saying it is not crazy longer, it is not, like, 100 or a thousand times longer, but it is your behavior.
Hansol Ryu: But it's getting better.
Hansol Ryu: And Team and Fly, they were also working on making the approximation model,
Hansol Ryu: To work with the OpenSim.
Hansol Ryu: So they can import their version of the approximation code switch model into the OpenZoom to run the free body simulation.
CHP233d: This is great, thank you.
Hansol Ryu: Moving?
Adwait Mane: I had a question, Dr. Ryu.
Hansol Ryu: Hey!
Hansol Ryu: For the answer, yeah.
Adwait Mane: Yeah, so I'm Mane from Northern Arizona University. Could you go to slide 12 of your presentation?
Hansol Ryu: Sorry, which one?
Adwait Mane: Slide 12, I think, is the one?
Hansol Ryu: Great.
Adwait Mane: I was just… I didn't fully understand what the distribution of bound cross bridges meetings.
Adwait Mane: So, I was wondering if you could explain that again.
Hansol Ryu: Okay, sure.
Adwait Mane: Yeah.
Hansol Ryu: Maybe something like this, yeah?
Adwait Mane: Yeah, exactly. So, you've got that plot there, the third one from the top, percentage cross-bish bound.
Adwait Mane: And, the x-axis is delta X, so that's the length change of… the cross bridge.
Hansol Ryu: Right, so… Yep, that's right.
Hansol Ryu: Closed bridges have various different lengths compared to their resting lengths.
Hansol Ryu: And then some of them are retested, and some of them are detached.
Hansol Ryu: And we can look at the distribution and count how many close bridges are within certain, rest, certain…
Hansol Ryu: displacement?
Hansol Ryu: Okay. From the listing links.
Hansol Ryu: and see… How many of them are obtests at that length?
Hansol Ryu: So we will discretize the lengths, so this one will be, say, at
Hansol Ryu: Length 5, and this one needs at length 0.
Hansol Ryu: And we count 1 and 1 here.
Hansol Ryu: And then look for the whole distribution, and look for the, like, ovalar distribution of the bound close bits.
Hansol Ryu: Did that help?
Adwait Mane: Yeah, I think so. So, the…
Adwait Mane: If that distribution is centered at zero.
Hansol Ryu: Right,
Adwait Mane: That means that… On average, all the brown cross bridges are… at equilibrium.
Hansol Ryu: Right, many, yeah, we have highest number of close bits that are bound at the center, or at the equilibrium.
Hansol Ryu: And that is because our attachment rate is highest at the equilibrium.
Hansol Ryu: And… That kind of makes sense, because it'll be easier to bind if they are, you know, aligned.
Adwait Mane: Yeah.
Hansol Ryu: And then it becomes easy to lose it when they are pulled too far away.
Adwait Mane: Okay.
Adwait Mane: So, when the distribution is centered at zero, you can still have force being generated.
Hansol Ryu: Right.
Adwait Mane: But what does that mean for, say, the shortening of the entire… Fiber.
Adwait Mane: Does it… Like, to me, it seems like if…
Adwait Mane: If it's centered at zero, the fiber's not going to shorten.
Adwait Mane: Is that correct?
Adwait Mane: It'll just be at its equilibrium length.
Hansol Ryu: So there are actually two types of forces going on here. One is the spleen-like force,
Hansol Ryu: So… and another one is the closed bridge cycling force. So, closed switch goes through the power cycle, like this.
Hansol Ryu: So it actually actively pulls the filament.
Hansol Ryu: So you will still get that force even if your forces are centered along zero. So, even if your displacements are centered along zero.
Adwait Mane: Oh, great.
Hansol Ryu: Right, that, yeah, if we only look at the spring, like, force, maybe when it is real asymmetric.
Hansol Ryu: I think you can net zero first.
Adwait Mane: Well, I understand that you can generate force, but.
Adwait Mane: Will it shorten if it is centered at zero? Will the fiber shorten?
Hansol Ryu: When the fiber shortens, do you still…
Adwait Mane: It seems like if you want the fiber to shorten, the distribution has to be left-shifted.
Hansol Ryu: Yeah, it will get shifted to the left a little bit, yeah.
Adwait Mane: Okay. Okay.
Hansol Ryu: But yeah, when it goes too far away, detachment rate increases.
Adwait Mane: Okay.
Hansol Ryu: We will start losing it, and then they will populate again near the center.
Adwait Mane: Oh, okay.
Adwait Mane: Oh, okay, interesting, as well.
Adwait Mane: Like, feedback, sort of, going on.
Hansol Ryu: Right, right, yeah.
Adwait Mane: Thank you.
Hansol Ryu: Cool, thank you.
Hansol Ryu: Right? Any other fun science?
Hansol Ryu: Should we finish here, Victoria?
Victoria Wood: Yeah, yeah, I think we're already running a few minutes late here, so…
Victoria Wood: Thank you all so much for attending, and thank you, Hansol, for a great talk here.
Victoria Wood: I'll post…
Hansol Ryu: Good evening.
Victoria Wood: Yeah, I'll post this, recording for people who weren't able to make it, and if anybody wants to go back and try out the, the code again. Thanks all.
Victoria Wood: Have a good day.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: Thanks, everybody. Thank you, Hansol and Victoria.
Hansol Ryu: Thank you!